# Richa Ojha

Bangalore | rchoiha16@gmail.com | +91- 9990007754

## **UX Content Designer**

6+ years of combined experience in content-focused roles, including 3+ years as a UX Writer in crafting content across a range of platforms including desktop and mobile (Android and iOS). Successfully transformed the customer journey from confusing to intuitive through carefully crafted UX flows.

## **Work Experience**

Microsoft - UX Writer May 2021 - Present Innominds Software Pvt Ltd

Create content that's simple, straightforward, and human for a family of products. Embrace research and data to break up complex information and provide customers with just enough information to make decisions quickly.

- Integrate customer feedback and business requirements into both new and current product experiences.
- Write clear and concise micro-copy for different scenarios -informational, error/empty states, onboarding flows, & text input fields.
- Co-design content with the PMs, Designers, and Researchers
- Regularly keep a check on the product, report the progress and roadblocks
- Craft a language flow for a customer-centric product for different platforms
- Adhering to content style guidelines, use approved terms only, and stay updated about terms to avoid
- Well-versed with Figma and Office 365 to write and maintain a record of strings

Cybernetyx Technik Pvt Ltd, Bangalore Product Communication Manager Dec 2019-March 2021

In collaboration with different teams, create user manuals, QSGs, marketing collaterals, guidebooks, SM posts, blogs, brochures, video scripts, website, and app content. Working knowledge of SharePoint, Office 365, & Trello.

- Develop informational and promotional content including websites content, emailer, keyword-based blogs and articles, videos scripts, and infographics.
- Use SEO strategies to maximize the online visibility of the written piece
- Coordinate with marketing, design, and PMs to craft website content
- Manage Content Dashboard on Trello board
- Prepare User Manual, QSG of software products

#### Achievement highlights

- Co-designed product pages and E-commerce landing pages with PMs and Designers
- Managed different requirements of content single-handedly

XIPHIAS Software Technologies Pvt Ltd. -Bangalore Senior Content Writer NOV 2017 - Oct 2019

Created content for a digital payment project - for website and mobile - Android & iOS.

- Write in informal conversational content
- Write around the customer's primary intent -consider what the button labels and words mean to them
- Use the same terms consistently everywhere menu items, labels, and buttons.

# Richa Ojha

Bangalore | rchojha16@gmail.com | +91- 9990007754

- Brainstorm on scenarios when customers choose an option or select a link
- Research on competes and create product-specific content
- Determine needs and designs of text input fields
- Collaborate with Development, Marketing, and other teams to drive and support the development of new offers.
- UX writer/ Product writer, Video scriptwriter, Corporate Presentations, VC Investor Presentation
- Creating promotional and non-promotional content for voice, email, chat, social media channels

### Achievement highlights:

- Got **Creative Content Head** award for designing Special Offers page.
- Actively participated in marketing content.

The Pioneer News Paper, Ranchi Staff Reporter Oct 2008-March 2010

- Write articles, features, news analysis, Q&A
- Attending press conferences/events by vendors and other agencies
- Developing new contacts & Alliances
- Assist seniors in taking interviews of high-profile personalities, copy editing, proofreading.
- Comparing HITS and MISSES

#### Achievement Highlights

- Turned an internship into a full-time job
- Got my article published on the first page of a national newspaper an interview of a Congress leader

### Academic Background

University of Lucknow - 2010-2012 M.A. in Linguistics, Received Gold Medal

St. Xavier's College - 2006-2009 B.A. in Functional English

Personal Information

Date of Birth: Nov 16, 1989 Marital Status: Married